# SAHAJ I. ISMAEL

Age 28
Baghdad
0772 983 1990
sahajisam@yandex.com



# **PROFILE**

Very hard worker, accurate, punctual, I like everything to be arranged and sorted out. I always do my best in my job. I can work as Interpreter, translator, coordinator, Logistic, administrative, & IT. I have good work experience in a multi-cultural work environment where I learned and became aware of many new good concepts like team work, cultural sensitivity, gained good communication skills and good ability in work planning and organizations.

# AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Translation/interpretation (English, Arabic, Russian)
- IT implementations
- Procurement and Logistics
- Administration
- Costumer Support
- Project Development

# **EDUCATION**

Voronezh State University, Faculty of Roman-Germanic Languages, 2015-2017 Master Degree in English Philology, program: "Intercultural Business Communication & Translation".

University of Mustansiriya, Baghdad, IRAQ, 2008-2012

**Bachelor in Translation** 

Voronezh State University, Voronezh, RUSSIA, 2014-2015

**Certificate in Russian Language - Level 2** 

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Deputy Manager in Supply Chain Department, Antonoil International, IRAQ, June 2013-November 2014

I worked in Antonoil International company for Oil and wells Services at Al-Halfaya Oilfield Base Camp near Kahlaa' town southern Iraq. I started my work at the Commercial department as a Commercial Assistant. Being a Commercial Assistant I was generally responsible for fulfilling custom clearance services for our shipments.

#### Roles:

- Making the necessary official documents for our shipments such as a Commercial Invoice, Packing list, Proof of Delivery, Levy Exemption, Authorization and Extension letters.
- Following up the procedures of our shipments once it is shipped from the source country until its delivery in our camp.
- Referring to the local authorities to coordinate and facilitate the progress of our shipments procedures.
- I also worked on the procurement field, I provided our teams and employees with the materials they need. I had coordinated with suppliers to provide us with the best services and materials.

# HR Manager, STX Marine Services, Missan, Iraq, 2012-2013

I started my work in STX Marine Service company at North Amarah Diesels Power Plant in July 16, 2012. I commenced my work as a data entry. Thereafter, I was assigned as the HR administrator of the company.

#### Roles:

- Arranging and finding employees for the company. We held interviews almost regularly every one month. I was responsible for arranging and running the interview.
- I managed the administration work regarding our employees such as the work schedule, vacations, time sheets, salaries, promotions, certifications and ID cards.
- I used to coordinate and facilitate the relation between our company and the Ministry of Electricity in the aspects of our employees database.

## Roles as an Interpreter:

- I interpreted meetings between STX and MOE that were held regularly in our company every month
- I interpreted meetings between the foreign managers and the Iraqi employees.
- I interpreted safety training courses for the Iraqi engineers.
- I helped making and translating official administration and technical letters sent by our company.

# Translator, ICONIA bureau for IT & Office services, Baghdad, Iraq, 2011-2012

I worked in a local office for computers and office services in Baghdad. I worked as a data entry and a translator.

## **Roles:**

- Typed Academic Researches in a quite official and professional pattern. I typed 2 P.hD theses and 3 Master Theses, in addition to many small researches in various languages.
- I translated many researches and abstracts for academic studies from Arabic into English and vise versa.
- I also provided assistance with the computer's software maintenance such as formatting, installing and fixing windows problems...etc.

## **TRAINING:**

- Microsoft Office Excel Essential Training, at Linda.com
- Microsoft Office Access Essential Training, at Linda.com
- Microsoft Office Word Essential Training, at Linda.com

## **CERTIFICATIONS:**

Certificate of Carreer, STX Marine Services.

Safety Management Standard Training program, STX Marine Services.

Certificate of participation at the Institute of international Education at VSU, 2014.

## **SKILLS:**

Languages: Arabic – native

English – Fluency level Russian – Advanced level

Computer Skills:

Microsoft (word, Excel, Access, Powerpoint, publisher, outlook)

Zendesk Photoshop